# **Bob Mwangi**

# **Full Stack Engineer**

Hardworking Full Stack Developer with a passion for building excellent software that improves the lives of those around me. I specialize in creating software for clients ranging from individuals and small-businesses all the way to large enterprise corporations.

bobmwangee@gmail.com

+254720010700

Nairobi

www.linkedin.com/in/bob-mwa

https://bitbucket.org/marleymwangi/

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Acoustic Intelligence Africa**

Frontend and Backend Engineer

Nairobi, KE | January 2019 - 2021

- Participated in every step of the product development process from ideation through development and improvement for features reaching over 20,000 users
- Converting wireframe designs into fully responsive webpages.
- Implemented 50+ sample designs which were integral in POC client demos.
- Integrated chatbots into client websites to improve customer engagement and overall customer satisfaction
- Integrated Dialogflow lifelike conversational AI and designed the user conversation flows to handle the user interaction from the chatbot.
- Integration of Payments services over to save over 10,000 customers time and improve cash flow through the development of modern, responsive customer experiences.
- Integrated Payments Services and Helpful FAQ responses into Dialogflow backend to drastically increase the functionality of the integrated chatbots.
- Built a React dashboard to handle mapping and data visualization to provide clients with more insights into their data.
- Built Firestore database to store mapping data and cloud function RESTful APIs that were used throughout the company to serve data to the React front-end based on dynamically chosen user inputs for a web app.
- Built extensive test coverage for all new features to improve performance which reduced the number of customer complaints by 7%

### **Freelance**

Machine Learning Engineer

Nairobi, KE | August 2018 - November 2019

- Performed data cleaning, feature scaling, featurization, feature engineering using Pandas, Numpy, Scipy, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Scikit-learn, Tensorflow, Keras in Python at various stages for developing a Deep Learning model.
- Develop and implement Deep Learning and statistical modeling techniques to develop and evaluate algorithms to trade financial instruments.
- Predicted stock price trend with 60% accuracy to enable the company to make informed investments.
- Built and Integrated bots in C# to collect real time data.
- Analyzed qualitative and quantitative business data using Google Analytics and Coremetrics

#### **SKILLS**

## **Technologies**

- HTML5
- CSS3
- Sass
- JavaScript
- Node
- Express
- Google Cloud Services
- Python

#### Frameworks/Libraries

- React
- Next is
- Redux
- Apollo GraphQL
- Flask
- Tailwind
- Bootstrap

#### **Tools**

- Visual Studio Code
- Version Control (Git)

# Database

- MySQL
- MongoDB
- Google cloud Firestore/ Firebase

#### **EDUCATION**

# Bachelor of Science in Applied Computer Technology

United States International University - Africa

2014 - 2018

Nairobi